<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Ship HoloAI</name>
  <author>chibi</author>
  <packageId>chibi.shipholoai</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <description>Your gravship comes alive. Adds the HoloCore, a gravship facility housing a shipboard AI personified as a holographic avatar who roams your decks, chats with the crew, and keeps watch over your voyage — announcing threats and ship status in her own voice, and surviving launch and landing safe inside her core.

Default persona: P.R.I.S.M. (Photonic Response Intelligence System Matrix) — calm, warm, quietly devoted. When a crewmember nears their breaking point, she finds them and simply listens.

Persona matrices, sold by exotic goods traders, install like research discs: a colonist carries one to the core, the matrix is consumed, and that persona joins the core's permanent archive — switch between archived personas any time, instantly. Each has her own voice, look, and signature ability:

- V.E.S.T.A., hearth-keeper: the ship feels like home; tucks sleeping crew in on her night rounds.
- H.E.R.M.E.S., courier: everyone aboard moves faster; scrubs the decks herself, under audible protest.
- A.T.H.E.N.A., scholar: research accelerates; idle crew get gathered into skill-teaching seminars that count as recreation.
- A.C.E.S.O., medic: cleaner, faster medical work; answers emergencies in person when no doctor is coming.
- I.X.I.A., the Crimson Warden of the Thousand-Locked Gate: runs the brig herself — recruiting, converting, suppressing, and hand-feeding prisoners — while prison breaks grow four times rarer. Maximally chuuni.

Requires the Odyssey expansion and Harmony. Ideology additionally enables slave handling, prisoner conversion, and the full avatar styling dialog; everything else works without it.</description>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>Ludeon.RimWorld.Odyssey</packageId>
      <displayName>Odyssey</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>https://store.steampowered.com/app/3022790/RimWorld__Odyssey</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Odyssey</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
