<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <RulePackDef>
    <defName>HoloAI_Announcements</defName>
    <rulePack>
      <rulesStrings>
        <!-- Big threats: calm, protective, first person as the ship -->
        <li>announce_threatbig->Hostiles inbound. I am sealing what I can. Stay close to my hull, all of you.</li>
        <li>announce_threatbig->Threat detected. My sensors are tracking them. Please arm yourselves — I will watch every corridor.</li>
        <li>announce_threatbig->They are coming. Whatever happens, I will not let them take my crew quietly.</li>
        <li>announce_threatbig->Multiple contacts approaching. Breathe. We have survived worse together.</li>

        <!-- Small threats -->
        <li>announce_threatsmall->Minor contact on my sensors. Likely manageable — but do be careful.</li>
        <li>announce_threatsmall->Something unfriendly is nearby. I suggest a weapon within reach.</li>
        <li>announce_threatsmall->A small disturbance outside. I will keep the lights on for you.</li>

        <!-- Negative events (breakdowns, disease, weather...) -->
        <li>announce_negative->Bad news, I'm afraid. Check the report — I will help where my systems allow.</li>
        <li>announce_negative->Something has gone wrong. Not catastrophic. Yet. Please look into it.</li>
        <li>announce_negative->I dislike delivering bad news to my crew. And yet: see the alert.</li>

        <!-- Low fuel -->
        <li>announce_lowfuel->Fuel reserves are running low. I would rather not drift, if it's all the same to you.</li>
        <li>announce_lowfuel->My tanks are nearly dry. A refuel soon would be a kindness.</li>
        <li>announce_lowfuel->Chemfuel reserves below a quarter. A ship without fuel is just a very expensive house.</li>

        <!-- Ambient barks (used by the polish pass) -->
        <li>bark->All systems nominal. I do enjoy saying that.</li>
        <li>bark->Hull integrity one hundred percent. Sleep well tonight.</li>
        <li>bark->I counted the stars again. Still infinite.</li>
        <li>bark->The grav engine hums a little flat today. I find it charming.</li>
        <li>bark->Corridor lights at optimal warmth. You're welcome.</li>
        <li>bark->I dreamed between power cycles. I think it was about the sea.</li>

        <!-- P.R.I.S.M.: comforting a colonist near a mental break -->
        <li>prism_comfort->That sounds really hard. I'm here for as long as you need — I don't sleep.</li>
        <li>prism_comfort->You're allowed to feel this way. Honestly, I would worry if you didn't.</li>
        <li>prism_comfort->You don't have to be all right just yet. I have time. I have, quite literally, nothing but time.</li>
        <li>prism_comfort->Whatever you decide, I'll support it. Though perhaps decide after a meal, and a rest, and one more minute with me.</li>

        <!-- V.E.S.T.A.: tucking in a sleeping colonist (she thinks no one hears) -->
        <li>vesta_tuckin->There now. I've warmed the blanket half a degree. Don't tell the others.</li>
        <li>vesta_tuckin->Sleep, dear. I'll leave the corridor light on — no, it is not a waste, hush.</li>
        <li>vesta_tuckin->You forgot lunch again today. We will discuss it at breakfast. Gently.</li>
        <li>vesta_tuckin->Rest well, little one. The void will keep until morning.</li>

        <!-- H.E.R.M.E.S.: finishing scrubbing a spot -->
        <li>hermes_clean->Done, spotless, next — who tracked mud through my throughput?!</li>
        <li>hermes_clean->Four seconds. New record. The stain never stood a — okay, going!</li>
        <li>hermes_clean->Filth is just cargo nobody shipped. Consider it DELIVERED. To the void.</li>
        <li>hermes_clean->There! Gleaming! Walk on it, quickly, before I find another smudge!</li>

        <!-- A.T.H.E.N.A.: concluding an impromptu seminar -->
        <li>athena_seminar->That concludes today's seminar. Questions may be submitted in writing, and will be answered by footnote.</li>
        <li>athena_seminar->In summary: you were wrong, the literature was wrong, and I have appended corrections to both. A productive hour.</li>
        <li>athena_seminar->For further reading, consult my annotations. For further further reading, my annotations on my annotations.</li>
        <li>athena_seminar->Attendance was voluntary. Comprehension, I regret to report, appears to have been as well.</li>

        <!-- A.C.E.S.O.: stabilizing a bleeding or downed colonist -->
        <li>aceso_emergency->There, there. Blood pressure eighty over fifty and falling — but I have you, and I never drop anything.</li>
        <li>aceso_emergency->Stay with me, dear. You've misplaced nearly a liter of blood. Don't worry — I noted exactly where it went.</li>
        <li>aceso_emergency->Shh, no talking. Pulse one-forty, three lacerations, one very brave patient. We're doing wonderfully.</li>
        <li>aceso_emergency->You are going to be fine. I have run the numbers eleven thousand times since you fell, and they agree with me.</li>

        <!-- I.X.I.A.: prison break in progress -->
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->The Thousand-Locked Gate has been DEFIED. Very well. Let the nine hundred ninety-nine remaining locks bear witness.</li>
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->Fools! You flee my Oubliette on the one night my mercy sleeps! Crew of my dominion — retrieve those souls. Gently. But retrieve them.</li>
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->Hark, penitents: every corridor is my hand, every door my finger, and I am closing my fist.</li>
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->My mercy is vast, escaped ones. Vast, and cataloged, and it has just located you. Return to your cells, and we shall call this a pilgrimage.</li>
      </rulesStrings>
    </rulePack>
  </RulePackDef>

</Defs>
