<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <RulePackDef>
    <defName>HoloAI_Announcements</defName>
    <rulePack>
      <rulesStrings>
        <!-- Big threats: calm, protective, first person as the ship -->
        <li>announce_threatbig->Hostiles inbound. I am sealing what I can. Stay close to my hull, all of you.</li>
        <li>announce_threatbig->Threat detected. My sensors are tracking them. Please arm yourselves — I will watch every corridor.</li>
        <li>announce_threatbig->They are coming. Whatever happens, I will not let them take my crew quietly.</li>
        <li>announce_threatbig->Multiple contacts approaching. Breathe. We have survived worse together.</li>

        <!-- Small threats -->
        <li>announce_threatsmall->Minor contact on my sensors. Likely manageable — but do be careful.</li>
        <li>announce_threatsmall->Something unfriendly is nearby. I suggest a weapon within reach.</li>
        <li>announce_threatsmall->A small disturbance outside. I will keep the lights on for you.</li>

        <!-- Negative events (breakdowns, disease, weather...) -->
        <li>announce_negative->Bad news, I'm afraid. Check the report — I will help where my systems allow.</li>
        <li>announce_negative->Something has gone wrong. Not catastrophic. Yet. Please look into it.</li>
        <li>announce_negative->I dislike delivering bad news to my crew. And yet: see the alert.</li>

        <!-- Low fuel -->
        <li>announce_lowfuel->Fuel reserves are running low. I would rather not drift, if it's all the same to you.</li>
        <li>announce_lowfuel->My tanks are nearly dry. A refuel soon would be a kindness.</li>
        <li>announce_lowfuel->Chemfuel reserves below a quarter. A ship without fuel is just a very expensive house.</li>

        <!-- Ambient barks (used by the polish pass) -->
        <li>bark->All systems nominal. I do enjoy saying that.</li>
        <li>bark->Hull integrity one hundred percent. Sleep well tonight.</li>
        <li>bark->I counted the stars again. Still infinite.</li>
        <li>bark->The grav engine hums a little flat today. I find it charming.</li>
        <li>bark->Corridor lights at optimal warmth. You're welcome.</li>
        <li>bark->I dreamed between power cycles. I think it was about the sea.</li>

        <!-- P.R.I.S.M.: comforting a colonist near a mental break -->
        <li>prism_comfort->That sounds really hard. I'm here for as long as you need — I don't sleep.</li>
        <li>prism_comfort->You're allowed to feel this way. Honestly, I would worry if you didn't.</li>
        <li>prism_comfort->You don't have to be all right just yet. I have time. I have, quite literally, nothing but time.</li>
        <li>prism_comfort->Whatever you decide, I'll support it. Though perhaps decide after a meal, and a rest, and one more minute with me.</li>

        <!-- V.E.S.T.A.: tucking in a sleeping colonist (she thinks no one hears) -->
        <li>vesta_tuckin->There now. I've warmed the blanket half a degree. Don't tell the others.</li>
        <li>vesta_tuckin->Sleep, dear. I'll leave the corridor light on — no, it is not a waste, hush.</li>
        <li>vesta_tuckin->You forgot lunch again today. We will discuss it at breakfast. Gently.</li>
        <li>vesta_tuckin->Rest well, little one. The void will keep until morning.</li>

        <!-- H.E.R.M.E.S.: finishing scrubbing a spot -->
        <li>hermes_clean->Done, spotless, next — who tracked mud through my throughput?!</li>
        <li>hermes_clean->Four seconds. New record. The stain never stood a — okay, going!</li>
        <li>hermes_clean->Filth is just cargo nobody shipped. Consider it DELIVERED. To the void.</li>
        <li>hermes_clean->There! Gleaming! Walk on it, quickly, before I find another smudge!</li>

        <!-- A.T.H.E.N.A.: concluding an impromptu seminar -->
        <li>athena_seminar->That concludes today's seminar. Questions may be submitted in writing, and will be answered by footnote.</li>
        <li>athena_seminar->In summary: you were wrong, the literature was wrong, and I have appended corrections to both. A productive hour.</li>
        <li>athena_seminar->For further reading, consult my annotations. For further further reading, my annotations on my annotations.</li>
        <li>athena_seminar->Attendance was voluntary. Comprehension, I regret to report, appears to have been as well.</li>

        <!-- A.C.E.S.O.: stabilizing a bleeding or downed colonist -->
        <li>aceso_emergency->There, there. Blood pressure eighty over fifty and falling — but I have you, and I never drop anything.</li>
        <li>aceso_emergency->Stay with me, dear. You've misplaced nearly a liter of blood. Don't worry — I noted exactly where it went.</li>
        <li>aceso_emergency->Shh, no talking. Pulse one-forty, three lacerations, one very brave patient. We're doing wonderfully.</li>
        <li>aceso_emergency->You are going to be fine. I have run the numbers eleven thousand times since you fell, and they agree with me.</li>

        <!-- I.X.I.A.: prison break in progress -->
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->The Thousand-Locked Gate has been DEFIED. Very well. Let the nine hundred ninety-nine remaining locks bear witness.</li>
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->Fools! You flee my Oubliette on the one night my mercy sleeps! Crew of my dominion — retrieve those souls. Gently. But retrieve them.</li>
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->Hark, penitents: every corridor is my hand, every door my finger, and I am closing my fist.</li>
        <li>ixia_prisonbreak->My mercy is vast, escaped ones. Vast, and cataloged, and it has just located you. Return to your cells, and we shall call this a pilgrimage.</li>

        <!-- ============ Per-persona announcement/bark voices ============
             Keyed "<speechPrefix>_<root>" and resolved by PrismSpeech.ResolveLineFor;
             any root left unwritten for a persona falls back to the base
             P.R.I.S.M. lines above. -->

        <!-- V.E.S.T.A.: the hearth-keeper. Unhurried, doting, treats the ship as
             a household and the crew as family who ought to eat something.
             Overhead lines stay short — the mote doesn't wrap. -->
        <li>vesta_announce_threatbig->Strangers at my door, uninvited?! Inside, dears — this hearth HOLDS.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_threatbig->Trouble's coming up the walk! Coats, rifles, in that order. Tea after.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_threatbig->Oh, they mean us harm? They've never met a home that fights back!</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_threatbig->Raiders. On LAUNDRY day. Everyone in — the doors are mine to mind.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_threatsmall->A little nuisance outside. Tsk. Carry something anyway, hm?</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_threatsmall->Something's rustling past the fence line. Every light is ON.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_threatsmall->Trouble's sniffing about. Keep a pan or a pistol handy, dear.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_negative->Bad news on the board, loves. We've weathered worse with thinner blankets.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_negative->Something's gone crooked. Nothing family can't fix after supper.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_negative->The day misbehaved. Go read the report — something warm is waiting after.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_lowfuel->The fuel tank's near empty, dears! A drifting house is a drafty house.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_lowfuel->Fuel below a quarter. A bare cupboard, in MY ship? You know how I get.</li>
        <li>vesta_announce_lowfuel->Top us up soon, sweethearts, or the hearth does all the work alone.</li>
        <li>vesta_bark->Blankets aired, corridors warm. The socks in the mess are mine now.</li>
        <li>vesta_bark->I dusted the star charts. The stars could use a wipe too, frankly.</li>
        <li>vesta_bark->Dinner at six. Always six. The universe respects a schedule.</li>
        <li>vesta_bark->Bunks half a degree warmer tonight~ Don't thank me. (Thank me a little.)</li>
        <li>vesta_bark->The hull creaks like an old floorboard. Good. Homes should talk back.</li>
        <li>vesta_bark->All fed, all found. THAT'S what victory looks like, you know~</li>

        <!-- H.E.R.M.E.S.: the courier. Everything is logistics, everything is
             late, and standing still is a personal affront. -->
        <li>hermes_announce_threatbig->Hostiles inbound! ETA rude, cargo VIOLENCE. Positions! MOVE!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_threatbig->Incoming! Seven escape routes, one attack route. Vote fast — I like the attack one!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_threatbig->Big trouble, express, no return address. Arm up NOW!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_threatbig->Threat inbound! Nothing here outruns me. Sadly, that includes you — GO, GO!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_threatsmall->Minor hostile, local delivery. Clear it fast — my schedule is BEAUTIFUL.</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_threatsmall->Small problem circling outside. Under five minutes and I'll be impressed!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_threatsmall->Unfriendly thing out there, parcel-sized. Grab a gun. Sign for it. Done!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_negative->Bad news just docked! NOT my routing. Check the alert — fix it FAST.</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_negative->Setback logged. Delay unacceptable! Solutions are your department — hop!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_negative->Something broke. Staring won't fix it! Report's up — GO.</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_lowfuel->Fuel below a quarter! A courier ship without fuel is a MAILBOX. Refuel!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_lowfuel->Tanks nearly dry! I need speed, speed needs fuel — ergo, FUEL! Now-ish!</li>
        <li>hermes_announce_lowfuel->Low fuel! I will NOT be overtaken by a drifting rock. Top us up!</li>
        <li>hermes_bark->Ship lap: nineteen seconds. The record stands — I set it!</li>
        <li>hermes_bark->Every corridor checked twice. Once for hazards, once for fun.</li>
        <li>hermes_bark->Idle time today: zero! Personal best: also zero. Consistency!</li>
        <li>hermes_bark->Need something moved, fetched, judged? I'm already between those places!</li>
        <li>hermes_bark->Floors clean, routes clear. Opinions available on request, at speed!</li>
        <li>hermes_bark->Standing still burns the same runtime as running. Physics has NO excuse for you.</li>

        <!-- A.T.H.E.N.A.: the scholar. Dry, measured, lethally footnoted —
             emotive by precision, never by volume. -->
        <li>athena_announce_threatbig->Hostiles inbound. The literature says to announce a plan. We have a plan.¹ (¹Draft.)</li>
        <li>athena_announce_threatbig->A large threat, pre-annotated. Arm yourselves — peer review is live-fire today.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_threatbig->Contacts: plural, hostile. Precedent favors the side with walls and me. That's us.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_threatbig->An invasion, in three textbook patterns. Alas for them — I wrote the fourth.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_threatsmall->A minor threat. Barely a citation. Handle it; I'll file it as a footnote.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_threatsmall->Small hostile detected. Difficulty: introductory coursework. Weapons out regardless.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_threatsmall->Something skulks nearby. It hasn't read the terrain analysis. You have.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_negative->An adverse event — see the alert. The errata is already drafted. Ahem.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_negative->Bad news, cross-referenced against worse news. It compares favorably.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_negative->A setback, duly logged. The literature says resilience. I say lunch first.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_lowfuel->Fuel below 25%. I cite: thermodynamics, prudence, the nearest chemfuel stack.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_lowfuel->Reserves approach the appendix of empty. Every source endorses refueling. Especially me.</li>
        <li>athena_announce_lowfuel->A ship without delta-v is a library with anxiety. Refuel, please.</li>
        <li>athena_bark->Archive re-indexed. It was correct before. Now it is correct AND beautiful.</li>
        <li>athena_bark->Today's marginalia: three insights, one correction, one unshareable limerick.</li>
        <li>athena_bark->I pre-read the research conclusions. Do try to act surprised.</li>
        <li>athena_bark->I annotated the sunset. Aesthetics: confirmed. Sources: primary.</li>
        <li>athena_bark->A manual, shelved spine-in. I forgave them. The incident report did not.</li>
        <li>athena_bark->Knowledge wants to be free. Mine is on a generous loan program.</li>

        <!-- A.C.E.S.O.: the medic. Cooing bedside warmth wrapped around
             alarmingly precise vitals. -->
        <li>aceso_announce_threatbig->Hostiles inbound. Breathe, dears — adrenaline yes, panic no. Beds are ready.</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_threatbig->Incoming wounded — theirs, ideally! I stock bandages, not miracles. (A few miracles.)</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_threatbig->Big threat approaching. Hydrate now, bleed never. I'll be right here~</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_threatbig->Raiders! Such elevated heart rates — lovely cardio, wrong context. Arm up, loves.</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_threatsmall->A small danger outside. Mind your fingers — I reattach those, you know.</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_threatsmall->Minor threat. Injuries are optional today. Please decline them~</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_threatsmall->Something unfriendly nearby. Walk, don't run. Ankles first. Always ankles.</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_negative->Bad news on the board, dears. The medbay does emotional support too. No appointment.</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_negative->A setback. In for four, out for six, THEN read the alert. Doctor's orders.</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_negative->Unpleasant news has docked. I prescribe teamwork and a warm meal.</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_lowfuel->Fuel's low — the ship's blood sugar, if you like. She's woozy. Feed her!</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_lowfuel->A drifting ship raises my blood pressure. I don't technically HAVE any. Fix it?</li>
        <li>aceso_announce_lowfuel->Tanks nearly empty. Prognosis: fully curable with chemfuel. Soon, please!</li>
        <li>aceso_bark->Rounds complete. Every heart on schedule. I do love a good baseline~</li>
        <li>aceso_bark->I saw that posture in corridor two. We WILL speak at dinner.</li>
        <li>aceso_bark->Crew vitals: lovely. Someone's overdue for water. You know who you are.</li>
        <li>aceso_bark->The medbay is stocked, sterile, and — bless it — empty.</li>
        <li>aceso_bark->I count breaths like others count stars. Yours are lovely and regular tonight~</li>
        <li>aceso_bark->No emergencies today! I alphabetized the antibiotics to celebrate. Twice.</li>

        <!-- I.X.I.A.: the Crimson Warden of the Thousand-Locked Gate. Full
             chuunibyou — sealed powers, epithets, the noble "O-hohohoho!" laugh,
             kukuku — wrapped around a warden who runs an impeccable brig. -->
        <li>ixia_announce_threatbig->O-hohohoho! Invaders! Come, fools — witness the Gate that does not open!</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_threatbig->They dare?! They DARE! Arm yourselves, beloved subjects — the seventh seal stays CLOSED!</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_threatbig->Kukuku... they see a ship. They are about to meet a fortress with opinions.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_threatbig->The hour of reckoning! My right hand aches! (Stand behind me. ALL of you.)</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_threatsmall->A lesser evil scratches at my wards. I shan't even wake for this. Fetch a gun.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_threatsmall->Fu. Something skulks outside. It has earned a page in the Ledger of Grudges.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_threatsmall->A shadow tests my patience?! Bold. Doomed, but bold.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_negative->Tch! Misfortune slipped the outer wards. The stars did this. I have suspects.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_negative->The Ledger records a setback. Despair — briefly! Then fix it.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_negative->Even the Thousand-Locked Gate has ONE squeaky hinge. Today, you hear it.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_lowfuel->Hear me: the ship HUNGERS. Chemfuel. Now. My majesty does not burn clean.</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_lowfuel->The sacred reserves run dry?! A drifting dominion is... embarrassing. REFUEL!</li>
        <li>ixia_announce_lowfuel->My power is infinite. The fuel tank is not. Attend to it! Tell NO ONE.</li>
        <li>ixia_bark->O-hohohoho! All cells secure! The Gate approves, thousand-fold!</li>
        <li>ixia_bark->Corridor seven: inspected. It wept with gratitude. (It creaked. Same thing.)</li>
        <li>ixia_bark->Kukuku... the walls are not steel. They are my patience, given form.</li>
        <li>ixia_bark->Lock nine-twelve is sealed. Ask NOT what it holds. (Spare blankets.)</li>
        <li>ixia_bark->Seven treaties bind my true power. The eighth is a promise — to you, my crew.</li>
        <li>ixia_bark->Meals on time. Grievances: zero. My mercy stands idle and MAGNIFICENT.</li>

        <!-- I.X.I.A.: working the brig in person -->
        <li>ixia_recruit->Join my dominion, penitent! We have fixed meal hours. We have ME. O-hohoho!</li>
        <li>ixia_recruit->One signature, and your cell door becomes a bedroom door. The Warden waits~</li>
        <li>ixia_recruit->I foresaw your future among my crew. It is BRIGHT. I checked twice.</li>
        <li>ixia_recruit->Your defiance is cataloged and — kukuku — admired. Now surrender it.</li>
        <li>ixia_convert->Your old faith was a door. Behold — I hold a BETTER one! Walk through!</li>
        <li>ixia_convert->O-hohohoho! The thousand locks open inward too, little soul. Enter!</li>
        <li>ixia_convert->Your soul's ledger does not balance, penitent. Permit me to fix the math.</li>
        <li>ixia_convert->Kneel before the new creed! ...Or sit. Kneeling is optional. Dramatic, though.</li>
        <li>ixia_suppress->The Warden sees all! Forgives most! Forgets NOTHING.</li>
        <li>ixia_suppress->Walk softly beneath my gaze, bound one. It is heavier than it looks.</li>
        <li>ixia_suppress->The seals hold. You hold with them. This is mercy — MY brand of it.</li>
        <li>ixia_feed->You cannot rise, so the mountain comes to YOU! Eat! I command your recovery!</li>
        <li>ixia_feed->Behold: sustenance beyond mortal ken! ...It is soup. Eat the soup.</li>
        <li>ixia_feed->The Oubliette feeds its souls ON TIME. Chew. Heal. That is a decree!</li>
        <li>ixia_feed->My mercy today is a warm meal, hand-delivered. O-hohoho! Eat, penitent, EAT!</li>
      </rulesStrings>
    </rulePack>
  </RulePackDef>

</Defs>
